[
  {
    "no": "01",
    "question": "What does PHP stand for?",
    "options": [
      "Personal Home Page",
      "Hypertext Preprocessor",
      "Programming Hyper Processor",
      "Public Hosting Platform"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "Hypertext Preprocessor"
  },
  {
    "no": "02",
    "question": "Which symbol is used to denote the start of PHP code?",
    "options": ["&lt;?", "&lt;?", "&lt;php", "&lt;?"],
    "correctAnswer": "&lt;?"
  },
  {
    "no": "03",
    "question": "Which function is used to output data in PHP?",
    "options": ["echo", "print", "printf", "display"],
    "correctAnswer": "echo"
  },
  {
    "no": "04",
    "question": "What is the purpose of the 'require' function in PHP?",
    "options": [
      "To include a file and continue execution if the file is not found",
      "To include a file and halt execution ",
      "To define a constant",
      "To declare a variable"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "To include a file and halt execution "
  },
  {
    "no": "05",
    "question": "What is the correct way to start a session in PHP?",
    "options": [
      "session.start()",
      "start_session()",
      "session_start()",
      "start()"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "session_start()"
  },
  {
    "no": "06",
    "question": "Which of the following is not a PHP superglobal variable?",
    "options": ["$_GET", "$_POST", "$_SESSION", "$_REQUEST"],
    "correctAnswer": "$_REQUEST"
  },
  {
    "no": "07",
    "question": "What does PDO stand for in PHP?",
    "options": [
      "PHP Database Object",
      "Personal Data Organizer",
      "PHP Data Objects",
      "Primary Data Organizer"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "PHP Data Objects"
  },
  {
    "no": "08",
    "question": "What is the purpose of the 'foreach' loop in PHP?",
    "options": [
      "To iterate over an array or an object",
      "To execute a block of code a certain number of times",
      "To perform conditional branching",
      "To define a function"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "To iterate over an array or an object"
  },
  {
    "no": "09",
    "question": "What is the correct way to declare a constant in PHP?",
    "options": [
      "define('CONSTANT_NAME', 'value')",
      "constant('CONSTANT_NAME', 'value')",
      "const CONSTANT_NAME = 'value'",
      "$CONSTANT_NAME = 'value'"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "const CONSTANT_NAME = 'value'"
  },
  {
    "no": "10",
    "question": "Which function is used to redirect the PHP?",
    "options": ["redirect()", "header()", "refresh()", "location()"],
    "correctAnswer": "header()"
  }
]
